#### Contact

918130484048 (Home) jeetendra.s.jaiswal@gmail.c om

www.linkedin.com/in/jeetendrajaiswal-21747466 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Banking
Technical Support
Hindi Translation

# Jeetendra Jaiswal

5 Years Of Banking Experience. 5 Years experience in Translation, Production coordination and IT Troubleshoot support.

Gautam Buddha Nagar, Uttar Pradesh, India

# Summary

Currently working as Freelance Translator English (USA) to Hindi at Translated.com. Worked on Translating Airbnb Website interface project.

Worked as Translator from English to Hindi Language for publications based on Bible which is featured on website supporting more than 900 languagesWorked in converting text of PDF to other Digital formats like EPUB, WPUB and JWPUB supporting App.

Worked as production coordinator and provided IT support for Watchtower Bible & Tract Society Of India. A non-profit organisation which looks after spiritual needs of people and translates Bible based publications in more than 20 Indian Languages. Provided Trouble shoot and technical help for almost 100 users of Translation Software.

Team Leader for Banking Process and International payments through SWIFT Mode for Banks like J P Morgan and Citigroup. Also handled Team of International Fund Transfer for APAC regions.

# Experience

Appen
Search Engine Evaluator, Internet Analyst
June 2019 - Present
Work from home

As an internet analyst, performing basic tasks online such as providing feedback on search results, advertisements and web page content.

Translated
Freelance Hindi Translator
March 2019 - Present
India

Worked on Airbnb project which involved translating overall Airbnb website in Hindi Language.

Watchtower Bible and Tract Society
Hindi Translation, Production Coordination & IT Support
May 2013 - January 2019 (5 years 9 months)

Greater Noida India

Worked as Translator from English To Hindi Language for publications based on Bible. Coordinating all projects for Hindi Language and ensuring timely production of Printed Format, Digital Format and Audio Format. Uploading of all formats and maintaining the Web site. This website is the only site which is available in more than 900 languages. Also providing IT support to all Translators related software management, maintenance, upgrades. Coordinating with Head Office Computers Dept. and providing Desktop Technical help to other locations in India.

J.P. Morgan Team Leader December 2008 - March 2013 (4 years 4 months) Mumbai Area, India

Team Leader in Trade Finance Products like Import Collections. This included Scrutiny of Documents as per URC 522 and also making payment through SWIFT mode MT 202. Also worked as Team Leader in International Funds Transfer Dept for APAC region. This included investigation related to automated payment failure. Mostly handled SWIFT messages like MT 202, MT 103, MT 740, MT 747.

Vodafone Essar Cellular Limited Executive April 2007 - May 2008 (1 year 2 months) Mumbai Area, India

Worked for Payments Department for Post Paid Customers. Collating Data of payments made through various mode like Internet Payments, Cash, Credit Card, Kiosks, etc. Also clearing funds from suspense account and crediting funds to proper account after investigation. Handling queries from Customer Care Team related to unposted payments. Daily Generating revenue reports for CEO of Mumbai Circle.

Citigroup Global Services Limited / Tata Consultancy Services Limited

#### Band 1 Executive

December 2005 - March 2007 (1 year 4 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Trade Finance Dept. Involved in Import Collections Documents Processing and Handling Buyers Credit Documentation. Processing Documentation of clients of Citibank so that they meet Banking Standards. Handling of Claims which are sent in MT742, Amendments MT747 and Authorization MT 740

### Education

S I W S College of Commerce and Economics and Smt Thirumalai College of Science Plot No 337 Sewree Wadala Estate Mumbai 400 031

Bachelor of Commerce (B.Com.), Accounting (2002 - 2005)

S I W S College of Commerce and Economics and Smt Thirumalai College of Science Plot No 337 Sewree Wadala Estate Mumbai 400 031

High Secondary 10+2, Accounting and Business/Management · (2000 - 2002)

Saraswati Vidya Mandir English High School S.S.C, Basic Schooling · (1987 - 2000)